RG 004:064, Hartford Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Hartford Probate Court records.
1641-1940
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Hartford District)
735.25 cubic feet
Record books, 1677-1849; Probate files, 1641-1940.
RG004_064
Multiple
Historical Note
Hartford, Hartford County, Town settled by English 1635, named 1637, City incorporated May 1784
The Hartford Probate District was constituted 1666, as a County Court. The Hartford Probate District presently serves the municipality of Hartford.
City of Hartford, Probate District chronology:
1635 - May 1666 Hartford Colonial Jurisdiction
May 1666 - Present Hartford County Court & District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, 1677-1849. Contact the probate court for access to record books after Volume 50. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Other volumes include daily botters, 1863-1887, a journal, 1829-1832, and ledgers, 1863-1884.
Probate files, 1641-1940. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1641-1814 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard. This item is very incomplete from 1800 on.
Partial index, 1800-1920. This item was never completed. It covers surnames Abbate to Babcock, Adeline.
Arrangement
Record Books:
The record books are numbered consecutively from 4 to 50. There is also a Volume 39A.
The daily blotters and ledgers are not numbered but run chronologically.
The probate files are in two accessions, 1641-1920 and 1920-1940. Files are arranged alphabetically within each.
Other Finding Aid
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in accession T003017 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Hartford
Places:
Hartford (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1940 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
The probate files are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 4-127*, 1677-1917; probate files 1651-1915 (Accession T003017 only); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) have been microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
*The following volumes are not on microfilm: 56-57, 59-60, 62, 68, 69-71, 73, 75, 77-78, 81-83, 86-88, 90-93, 95-96, 98-99, 102-103, 105, 107-110, 112-114, 116, 118-122, 124, 126-129, 131-134, 136, 138-142, 144-151, 154-157, 159-162, 164-167, 169-173, 175-176, 178-181, 184-188, 190-191, 193-195, 197-201, 203, 205-209, 211, 213-216, 218-221, 224-235, 237-245, 247-259. 261-263, 265-275.
Provenance
The daily blotters and ledgers were deposited in the Connecticut State Library on March 31, 1925. The journal was deposited on December 19, 1938. It is not known when the record books, other volumes, or probate files were deposited.
Container List
- Record books, 1677-1849; 15.25 cubic feet (48 volumes); T003096
  Volumes 4, 5, and 6 contain records for Hartford County County Court as well as for the Probate Court.
  - Records, 1677-1697 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1689-1696 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1697-1702 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1700-1709 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1707-1716 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1692-1722 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1723-11729 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1729-1734 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1727-1737 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1736-1742 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1742-1753 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1742-1753 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1742-1753 (Volume 16)
  - Records, 1753-1757 (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1757-1764 (Volume 18)
  - Records, 1761-1770 (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1764-1770 (Volume 20)
  - Records, 1770-1774 (Volume 21)
  - Records, 1774-1788 (Volume 22)
  - Records, 1774-1788 (Volume 23)
  - Records, 1777-1793 (Volume 24)
  - Records, 1793-1800 (Volume 25)
  - Records, 1800-1802 (Volume 26)
  - Records, 1802-1806 (Volume 27)
  - Records, 1808-1811 (Volume 28)
  - Records, 1809-1811 (Volume 29)
  - Records, 1811-1813 (Volume 30)
  - Records, 1813-1815 (Volume 31)
  - Records, 1815-1818 (Volume 32)
  - Records, 1818-1821 (Volume 33)
  - Records, 1821-1824 (Volume 34)
  - Records, 1824-1826 (Volume 35)
  - Records, 1826-1829 (Volume 36)
  - Records, 1829-1831 (Volume 37)
  - Records, 1831-1833 (Volume 38)
  - Records, 1833-1834 (Volume 39)
  - Records, 1833-1834 (Volume 39A)
  - Records, 1634-1836 (Volume 40)
  - Records, 1836-1838 (Volume 41)
  - Records, 1838-1839 (Volume 42)
  - Records, 1839-1841 (Volume 43)
  - Records, 1841-1842 (Volume 44)
  - Records, 1842-1843 (Volume 45)
  - Records, 1843-1844 (Volume 46)
  - Records, 1844-1846 (Volume 47)
  - Records, 1846-1847 (Volume 48)
  - Records, 1847-1848 (Volume 49)
  - Records, 1849 (Volume 50)
- Daily blotters, 1863-1887; 2.5 cubic feet (9 volumes); 1925-022
  Judge J. Hurlburt White
  Volumes are not numbered
  Former call number: 345.42 fc753d
  Original accession numbers: 126535 through 126543
  - 1863-1868
  - 1868-1870
  - 1870-1873
  - 1873-1875
  - 1875-1877
  - 1877-1880
  - 1880-1882
  - 1882-1885
  - 1885-1887
- Journals, 1829-1832; .25 cubic feet (1 volume); 1938-002
  Volume is not numbered
  Former call number: 345.42 fc753j
  Original accession number: 213177
  - 1829-1832
- Ledgers, 1863-1884; 1 cubic foot (4 volumes); 1925-023
  Original accession numbers: 126544 through 126547
  - 1863-1864
  - 1866-1868
  - 1867-1873
  - 1873-1884
- Estate of Joseph Church, 1876-1900; 1 cubic foot (3 volumes); T003301
  - Journal, 1876-1891
  - Journal, 1892-1900
  - Ledger, 1876-1900
- Estate of Lawson C. Ives, 1904-1906; .25 cubic feet (1 volume); T003302
  - Trustee accounts, 1904-1906
- A digest of the early Connecticut probate records / compiled by Charles William Manwaring, 1904; 1 cubic foot (3 volumes); T003303
  Presented by compiler to the Connecticut State Library, 1904.
  A copy is available at and also at
  - 1635-1700 (Volume 1)
  - 1700-1729 (Volume 2)
  - 1729-1750 (Volume 3)
- Probate Files, 1641-1920; 339.5 cubic feet; T003017
  - Probate files, 1641-1920 (Box 1-679)
    Arranged alphabetically.
- Inventory Control Book, 1641-1920; T003073
  Index of the accessions now merged into T003017.
  Also known as the Godard Digest
  There are 2 items for Hartford Probate.
- Probate Files, 1920-1940; 374 cubic feet; T002501
  There is no index for these files.
  - Probate files, 1920-1940 (Box 1-748)
    There are 2 boxes numbered 744.
- Probate Files, 1935; .5 cubic feet; T003267
  - Estate of Harriet Day Hansel, 1935 (Box 1)